Hall, Keppele Papers 5607
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Keppele Hall Papers
1894-1980
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hall, Keppele
5607
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Work measurement and job analysis studies.
2298504
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 05, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 20, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Keppele Hall was an engineer, contractor, management theorist, superintendent of planning for Joseph & Feiss Company, and member of the National Board of Labor Managers. As a management consultant, he oversaw the implementation of management systems according to the principles enunciated by proponents of scientific management.
Scope and Contents
Professional papers consist primarily of fragmentary examples of work measurement and job analysis materials used in various manufacturing companies. The documents reflect Hall's effort to apply scientific management principles to practical activities.
Work measurement materials include tags, job instructions, data and miscellaneous notes and diagrams for the Tabor Mfg. Company (1912-1919), the Clinton Wire Cloth Company (1917), Lamson and Sessions Company (1926), and Strouse Brothers Inc. (1920); a contract for the Keppele Hall Contracting Company, Dayton, Ohio (1894-1913); and drafts and copies of the Articles of Federation of the National Industrial Federation of Clothing Manufacturers (1919). The papers also reflect Hall's association with Frederick Taylor's colleagues, Richard A. Feiss and Sanford E. Thompson.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Industrial management; Job analysis; Management science; Methods engineering; Work measurement.; Business consultants; Industrial engineers; Feiss, Richard A. (Richard Albert),1878-1954; Hall, Keppele,1872-1926.; Thompson, Sanford E. (Sanford Eleazer), 1867-1949
2298504
- Biographical information on Keppele Hall by C.D. Wrege and J.C. Mundy, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes working paper entitled "Management Consulting 1913- 1926:The Keppele Hall Papers" by C.D. Wrege and J.C. Mundy, 1980, 31 pp.
- Correspondence. General., 1914-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Includes correspondence with Frederick Taylor, Tracy Copp, Harold Marshall, Sidney Hillman. Includes notes on Mrs. Muskowitz. One letter mentions Ida Tarbell's interest in Scientific Management.
- Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1915-1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes Minutes of Baltimore Federation of Clothing Manufacturers note: This material is in order as taken out of one binder [folder 1 of 2]
- Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1915-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes Minutes of Baltimore Federation of Clothing Manufacturers note: This material is in order as taken out of one binder [folder 2 of 2]
- Keppele Hall Publications (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Terms in the Wire Cloth Industry by K. Hall, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    6 pp.
  - The Standardization of Papers by K. Hall, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    5 pp.
  - Reducing The Cost of Manufacture by K. Hall, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    16 pp.
  - Preliminary Report on Overall Industry by K. Hall, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Wage Systems by K. Hall, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    24 pp.
  - The Planning Department as an Instrument of Executive Control by K. Hall, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    8 pp.
- Article of Federation. National Industrial Federation of Clothing Manufacturers, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Clinton Wire Cloth Company: Time Cards, Work Reports, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Clinton Wire Cloth Company: Work Cards, Purchase Slips, etc., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Clinton Wire Cloth Company and Easton Manufacturing Company, Taylor System Forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Contract (blank) to Keppele Hall Company, Dayton, Ohio, 1894-1913 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Eastern Manufacturing Company. Keppele Hall Report and Paper Specifications, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Eastern Manufacturing Company. Standing Orders, 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Standing Orders.
- Job Tags, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lamson and Sessions Company, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Statistics and Data on Work Output and Report.
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 1 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 1 of 4]
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 2 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 2 of 4]
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 3 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 3 of 4]
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 4 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 4 of 4]
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Accounting System for the Newton Machine Tool Works by H.K. Hathaway, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  97 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: The Balance Clerk n.n., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  66 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data [folder 1 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: The Follow Up System, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    21 pp.
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: The Planning Department by H.K. Hathaway, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    30 pp.
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: "Bonus Time Notes and Bonus Record Cards (Box 1, Folder 21)
    4 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data [folder 2 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Report to Plymouth Cordage Company, North Plymouth, Mass., on Form of Organization by H.K. Hathaway, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    28 pp.
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Report on Care and Maintenance of Belting (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data [folder 3 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Routine and Bonus for Time Clerk, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Order of Work Clerk, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Recording Clerk, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Storekeeper, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  62 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Balance of Stores Clerk, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  47 pp.
- Study of Operations and Processes Used in the Manufacture of Clothing, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Morris Greenberg
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Miscellaneous Forms, 1912-1919 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Miscellaneous Forms, 1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Blueprint, 1908 (Mapcase folder 2)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Blank Forms, undated (Mapcase folder 3)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Blueprints and Charts, 1908; 1917 (Mapcase folder 4)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Blueprints and Charts, 1904-1919 (Mapcase folder 5)